myproperty.ph 2018-11-19

# Privacy Policy | MyProperty.ph

Privacy Policy A. Overview

At MyProperty.ph, your privacy is important to us and we want you to feel safe and secure when you use MyProperty.ph not only as a website but as a service. We encourage all of our users to read our privacy policy and be more aware regarding their use of MyProperty.ph. All users include the property seeker, property seller, property advertisers, and other individuals who use or visit the website.

Upon availing oneself of the services and information offered at the Online Marketplace, the user is obligated to comply with these provisions or to forgo use thereof. Furthermore, in the event of non-compliance with the contractual provisions, s/he expressly agrees that the Provider may legally prohibit the user from using its services and may require compensation for damages and that the Provider also expressly reserves the right prosecute any unlawful use.

This privacy policy will cover how MyProperty.ph handles and treats all personal information collected and received as well as information that relates to the past use of our products and services.

In light of this we want all of our users to fully understand what kind of information we collect on our users, how we use this information, how it is safeguarded, and lastly how users have control of it.

The privacy policy stated on this website, applies only to this website. Other websites we link to maintain their own respective privacy policies.

B. What is Personal Information?

Personal Information, when referred to, is information that a user states that personally identifies oneself by one's own name, email, address, phone numbers, and other information that is not publicly available.

The information provided in the Online Marketplace represents neither an invitation to place an ad nor an offer nor a recommendation to rent and/or purchase an item, unless the Provider expressly identifies it unmistakably as an "offer" or "invitation to buy or sell". In case of doubt the user must assume that the Provider does not wish to enter into a binding agreement. The Provider is not a party to a contract that may be formed between the user and a third party publishing information in the Online Marketplace.

All information collected is dependent on the context of which it was collected and how the user utilizes the website. MyProperty.ph collects but is not limited to the following information when registering:

  * **Name**
  * **Location or Address**
  * **Gender**
  * **E-mail**
  * **Phone Number(s)**

When a user chooses to place their personal information when creating listings they are doing so under the assumption that the contact phone number they choose will be publicly seen on the listing along with their name.

We encourage our users to practice their own discretion when giving information and to not share their password. Once registered, you and your personal information are on the MyProperty.ph database.

C. Information Sharing Disclosure

MyProperty.ph uses this information to track the usage of the website for business and security purposes, to understand the behavior and customization of content of the website in order to improve the website and the user's experience by providing the best service possible.

The Provider is not liable for abuse of the Internet and associated damage incurred by the user - in particular due to viruses and other damaging elements - for security lapses and failures of third party telecommunications and of the Internet or for operating disruptions and failures of the Online Marketplace and/or third-party applications.

MyProperty.ph does emphasize that it does not share, sell, or rent your personal information with third parties or people not affiliated with us with the exception of the services you have requested.

MyProperty.ph does provide some information to our trusted business partners, who provide some services for our site. These partners do share our privacy policy on personal information regarding MyProperty.ph and do not have any independent right to share users' personal information. These business partners work on our behalf under confidentiality agreements.

We observe the law and will exercise our legal right to defend ourselves against legal claims.

MyProperty.ph will allow the sharing of information in order to investigate suspected fraud, illegal activities, violation of MyProperty.ph's terms of use, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or as otherwise required by law.

D. User Control of Personal Information

MyProperty.ph allows users to edit their personal information and gives them flexibility with the information they choose to state. Moreover, options are given as to whether they would like to receive our newsletters and participate in the forums.

Any information stated can be changed later on. Users can change their personal information anytime by logging in and going to _Menu > Your Account > Edit Information_

Users may also choose to unsubscribe from the newsletters following the instructions found in the newsletter when the unsubscribe link is clicked.

E. Security of Personal Information

MyProperty.ph uses a variety of technologies to secure your personal information and protect it from unauthorized access and use. Personal information is stored by a controlled facility and can only be accessed within our facility and cannot be accessed outside.

F. Newsletter

When a user subscribes to the MyProperty.ph Newsletter, they will only ask for the email address which the site will use to send the newsletters to. Subscriptions can be done either through the process of signing up as a member, or they can simply input their email address in the newsletter registration box.

G. E-mail A Friend

MyProperty.ph does provide the service of forwarding a friend a newsletter or sharing site content and will only ask for the friend's name and email address for the sole purpose of sending them the referral email. We only store the message content for purposes of tracking the success of the referral program. We do not store the names or e-mail addresses of the sender and receiver.

The function of forwarding some of MyProperty.ph website content is available to all users of the website. As such, MyProperty.ph does not have control on to whom users send website content through this function. If a user or a recipient suspects another user of inappropriately using this function, he/she may contact us at support@myproperty.ph to further investigate.

H. Third Party Providers

MyProperty.ph may use third parties to provide certain services for any of the following:

  * **Payment gateway service**
  * **Web analytics**
  * **Newsletters**
  * **Facebook Integration**

Third party service providers are prohibited from using your personal information for any other purpose.

Currently, MyProperty.ph uses Google Analytics as a third party web analytics service, which tracks the traffic of the site. It is used for internal use in analyzing the usage and performance of MyProperty.ph. Google Analytics does not have access to the personal information of our users.

MyProperty.ph has Facebook Integration, as a third party social network service, where users can choose to share their ads on MyProperty.ph via Facebook.

MyProperty.ph also uses iContact, a third-party e-mail newsletter service. It is used to design and release e-newsletters, and does not have access to the personal information of our users.

MyProperty.ph also uses Google AdWords and Google Display Network together to serve ads to you on other websites after you've visited our website. This practice is known as remarketing and is a tool that Google offers to businesses. If you would like to know more about the program, [**you can do so here**](https://support.google.com/adwords#topic=3119071). But here are the basics: we, along with third-party vendors, Google and DoubleClick, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on your past visits to our website. 

If you would like to opt-out of receiving advertising like this from Google, you can manage these settings by visiting the [**Google Ads Preferences Manager**](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated?hl=en). Also, Google recommends installing the [**Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on**](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

I. Changes Applied to the Privacy Policy

MyProperty.ph occasionally updates the Privacy Policy to reflect the feedback from its users and from the Company. As such, we will state which sections have been updated.

We encourage our users to read and review this Privacy Policy and stay well informed of how we protect you as our users. If in any way you believe that we have not adhered to this policy please contact us. MyProperty.ph welcomes your comments and inquiries regarding this Privacy Policy.

Telephone no.: **+63 (2) 8800650.**

E-mail: **info@myproperty.ph**

This Privacy Statement is in effect starting April 27, 2015, or until otherwise superseded with an update.

Frequently Asked Questions Does MyProperty.ph buy and sell the properties it advertises?

MyProperty.ph is designed to be an effective channel to bring property seekers and property advertisers together. It is not a developer, broker, or investor and as such, does not own, buy, or sell the properties advertised on the website.

Why do I need to register for a user account?

Registering for a user account in MyProperty.ph enables other features on the website when you're logged in. Some features are subscribing to e-mail alerts, saving your favorite property listings and Saved Searches, and even posting a free listing. Registering as a user is free.
